

GRADUATE RESEARCHER · MASTERS STUDENT

Beirut, Lebanon

🛮 🕻 (+961) 71-778924 | 💌 wissam.antoun@gmail.com | 🖸 WissamAntoun | 🛅 wissamantoun | 🞓 Wissam Antoun

Summary_

Current Masters Student at the American University of Beirut, with focus on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning and specialised in state-of-the-art Natural Language Processing techniques. 2 years of experience in teaching (Graduate Teaching Assistant) in the Electrical Engineering Department. Tech geek who loves computer hardware and technology, and enjoys DIY projects and gaming. Interested in learning new tools and technologies, and in increasing my problem solving skills.

Work Experience

Zaka Online

WORKSHOP INSTRUCTOR May. 2020

Gave a 4-part online workshop series titled *A Comprehensive NLP* series

Stars of Science Doha, Qata

MACHINE LEARNING EXPERT Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020

Provided ML and AI solutions to contestants as part of the support team

MIND Lab (Prof. Hazem Hajj) - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT Sep. 2018 - Current

Research focuses on SOTA NLP technologies for NLP, NLG, and social chatbots.

ECE Dept. - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- EECE 435L: Software Tools Lab, Co-Instructor (3 semesters)
- EECE 696: Applied Parallel Programming, Lab instructor (1 semester)
- EECE 330: Data Structures and Algorithms, Lab instructor (1 semester)

Huawei Technologies (Lebanon) S.A.R.L.

Beirut, Lebanon

INTERN

June 2016 - Aug. 2016

 Learned about various LTE principles, base station hardware, and Microwave transmissions systems.

Publications_

AraBERT: Transformer-based Model for Arabic Language Understanding. *Antoun*, *Wissam*, *Fady Baly, and Hazem Hajj Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020*, 2020, Marseille, France

Multi-Task Learning using AraBert for Offensive Language Detection.

Djandji, Marc, Fady Baly, **Wissam Antoun**, and Hazem Hajj Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

State of the Art Models for Fake News Detection Tasks. *Antoun, Wissam*, Fady Baly, Rim Achour, Amir Hussein, and Hazem Hajj 2020 IEEE International Conference on Informatics, IoT, and Enabling Technologies (ICIoT) (ICIoT'2020), 2020, Doha, Qatar

hULMonA: The Universal Language Model in Arabic. *ElJundi, Obeida, Wissam Antoun, Nour El Droubi, Hazem Hajj, Wassim El-Hajj, and Khaled Shaban Proceedings of the Fourth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop at ACL*, 2019, Florence, Italy

A Comprehensive Approach for A Smart Medication Dispenser. *Kassem, Abdallah, Wissam Antoun, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary International Journal of Computing and Digital Systems* 8.02 (2019) pp. 131–141. University of Bahrain, 2019

Smart Medicine Dispenser (SMD). *Antoun, Wissam, Ali Abdo, Suleiman Al-Yaman, Abdallah Kassem, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary 2018 IEEE 4th Middle East Conference on Biomedical Engineering (MECBME)*, 2018

Real-Time Fire Detection Using CUDA. *Antoun, Wissam* and Manal *JalloulISC High Performance*, Poster Presentation, 2019, Frankfurt, Germany

Honors & Awards

Best Domain Detection system, Qatar

International Fake News Detection and Annotation Doha, Qatan Contest, 2019

Second Place, Mindsets-OLX Datathon, Best car

price prediction score. AUB, Lebanon

www.kaggle.com/c/mindsets, 2019

First place, Big Data, AI, and Media Hackathon

AUB, Lebanon

Powered by Touch and Anghami, 2019

Presentation

High Performance Computing for Lebanon (HPC4L) Brown Bag

Beirut, Lebanon

PRESENTER FOR CURRENT AND FUTURE/POTENTIAL USE

SENTER FOR CORRENT AND FOTORE/POTENTIAL USE

Feb. 2020

CASES FOR HPC4L

Introduced the use case of HPC for pretraining transformer-based model for Arabic language Understanding

PyData Khobar meetup

Online

PRESENTER FOR ARABERT: PRETRAINING, USE CASES AND

May. 2012

FUTURE IMPROVEMENTS

Introduced the AraBERT model for the Arab community and explained the pretraining and fine-tuning procedure

Education

Masters Of Engineering In Electrical And Computer Engineering

Beirut, Lebanon

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT

Feb. 2018 - Current

A 1.6 1 . Ell. 1: 21 (11. 22

· Awarded Graduate Fellowship with full tuition coverage

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer And Communication Engineering

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY - LOUAIZE

Fall. 2014 - Summer 2017

• GPA: 3.58 Dean's List for 6 semesters

Skills_

• Proficient in: Python (TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras), NVidia CUDA (Parallel Programming), Matlab, C# and C++.

May 8, 2020 Wissam Antoun · Résumé

- Familiar with: Open ComputerVision ,Xilinx, C, VHDL, Java, Qt, SQL.
- Documentation Tools: LaTex, Doxygen, MS-Word.